Guide to the Louis H. Pollak Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Louis H. Pollak papers
1948-2012
MS 1989
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
26.5
(60 boxes)
The collection comprises the papers of attorney, legal scholar, and United States Circuit Court judge, Louis H. Pollak. The papers consist of correspondence and subject files documenting myriad aspects of his life and career, including his tenure as a professor and Dean at Yale Law School.
Pollak, Louis H.
Biographical / Historical
Louis Heilprin Pollak, a United States District Court judge and former dean of the Yale and University of Pennyslvania Law Schools, was born on December 7, 1922, in New York City. He received his undergraduate degree from Harvard University in 1943, and after serving in the United States Army, received his law degree from Yale. After graduating from law school, Pollak worked as a clerk for Justice Wiley B. Rutledge of the United States Supreme Court from 1948 to 1949, and thereafter accepted a position at the law firm, Paul, Weiss, Wharton & Garrison (known in 2013 as Paul, Weiss, Rifkind, Wharton & Garrison). It was during his tenure at this firm that Pollak was recruited by Thurgood Marshall to serve as a volunteer for the NAACP Legal Defense and Education Fund, which afforded him the opportunity to contribute significantly to several landmark civil rights cases.
Pollak was a member of the legal team that represented the plaintiffs in Brown v. Board of Education, the 1954 Supreme Court case that overturned legal segregation in American public schools. In 1965, he argued before the Supreme Court in the Abernathy v. Alabama case, which resulted in the reversal of criminal convictions of Freedom Riders who had campaigned to desegregate buses and bus stations in the South. Pollak also argued before the Supreme Court on behalf of the plaintiffs in McLaughlin v. Florida, in which the court unanimously repealed a law banning the cohabitation of people of different races.
Pollak joined the Yale Law School faculty in 1955 and was appointed dean in 1965, a position he held until 1970. In 1974, he joined the faculty of the University of Pennsylvania Law School and was named dean the following year. President Jimmy Carter appointed Pollak to the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania in 1978. During his 36-year tenure as a judge, Pollak was known as a staunch advocate of defendents' rights. In 1992, Pollak became a senior judge in semi-retirement, and in addition to his district court duties, sat by designation regularly with the United States Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit, and also often with the Ninth Circuit. Louis H. Pollak died on May 8, 2012, and at the time of his death, was survived by his wife, Katherine Weiss Pollak, five daughters, and seven grandchildren.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Katherine Weiss Pollak, 2012.
Arrangement
The papers are arranged in four series: I. Alphabetical correspondence, 1965-2012; II. Chronological correspondence, 1964-2004; Series III. Subject files, 1948-2004; IV. Supreme Court justice files, 1989-2012.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research with the exception of Box 60, which contains files of correspondence with current and former Justices of the United States Supreme Court. Correspondence with any current or former Justice of the United States Supreme Court shall remain closed to all research until the death of that Justice or former Justice.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository.
Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
Scope and Contents
The collection comprises the papers of attorney, legal scholar, and United States Circuit Court judge, Louis H. Pollak. The papers consist of correspondence and subject files documenting myriad aspects of his life and career, including his tenure as professor and dean at Yale Law School.
Judges; Law teachers; Lawyers; Pollak, Louis H.; Yale Law School; Yale University -- Faculty; Pollak, Louis H.
- Alphabetical correspondence, 1965-2012; 1980-2012; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of both incoming and outgoing correspondence, the bulk of which dates from the early 1980s through 2012, with a few items dating from the mid-1960s and the 1970s. The correspondence primarily concerns Pollak's scholarly work and professional engagement, through writing, speaking engagements, and discussions with colleagues about important legal issues of the day. There is also some correspondence pertaining to social matters. Correspondents of note include Robert Bork and William J. Brennan, Jr.
  Arrangement
  The papers are arranged alphabetically.
  - Adams, Arlin M., 1999-2009 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Angell, Faith, 2001-2011 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Arnold, Richard Sheppard, 2004, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Arnstein, Robert Leo, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Axelrod, Allan, 1988-2010 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Bakke, Allan, 1995, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bartle, Harvey, 2007, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Becker, Edward, 1982-2007 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Berkman, Alan, 2001, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bernstein, Elmer, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Biko, Stephen Bantu (regarding), 1978, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Bittker, Boris, 1985-2006 (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
  - Black, Charles L., 1986-2004 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Black, Hugo, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Blum, Pamela and John, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Boies, David, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bork, Robert H., 1987-1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Branton, Wiley Austin, 1992-1992 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Brennan, William J., Jr., 1979-2010 (Box 4, Folder 1-5)
  - Broderick, Raymond J., Jr., 2000-2001 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Brody, Anita B., 2003-2007 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Brown, Ralph S., 1983-2009 (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
  - Brudney, James J. and Ben, 1996-2010 (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - Burbank, Stephen B., 1985-2011 (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
  - Cades, Ida, 1983-1992 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Cahn, Edward, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Calabresi, Guido, 2010 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Campbell, Ann and Bill Leatherbee (wedding), 2011 September (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Cardozo, Michael H., 1994 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Carter, Robert L., 2012 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Clark, Elias, 2000-2001 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Clinton, President William J., 1994-2003 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Coffin, Reverend William S., Jr., 2006 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Coleman, William T., Jr., 2000-2010 (Box 7, Folder 6-9)
  - Coleman, William T., III, 1999-2003 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Colgan, Flavia, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Collins, Ronald K. L., 2005 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Cremer, Hans-Joachim, 2005-2008 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Davis, Legrome D., 2001-2006 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - DiMaggio, Joe, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Ditter, William J., Jr., 2005-2010 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Diver, Jason and Colin, Undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Dubois, Jan, 2010 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Edelman, Marian Wright, 2001 September (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Edwards, Henry, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Emerson, Thomas, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Errick, Steve, 2003 October (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Fagin, Charles and Frances Myung (wedding), 2003 September 6 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Farr, Walter G., Jr., 2003-2005 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Felstiner, William, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Ferren, John M., 2004-2009 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Fletcher, Betty B., 2007 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Fordham, Jefferson, 1965-1970 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Frank, John P., 2002-2005 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Frankfurter, Felix (regarding), Undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Freedman, James O., 1982-2007 (Box 9, Folder 3-5)
  - Freedman, Rina Stahl, 1999 November (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Freeman, Milton V., 1983 January (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Friendly, Henry, 1985-2011 (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
  - Fullam, John, 2006-2007 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Giles, James T., 2006-2009 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Ginger, Ann Fagin, 1980-2002 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Glazer, Tom (memorial), 2003 January 29 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Gold, Stephen F., 1995-1996 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Goldstein, Abraham (memorial), 2005 November 6 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Goldstein, Joel K., 2009 April 15 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Gordon, Sarah, 2001-2010 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Gorman, Robert, 2000-2010 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Gould, Martin, Undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Green, Clifford S., 2002-2007 (Box 11, Folder 4-6)
  - Greenberg, Jack, 2000-2011 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Gregorian, Vahe and Cynthia Billhartz (wedding), 2001 April 14 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Gregorian, Vartan, 1989-2004 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Guinier, Lani, 1991-1993 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Gutman, Amy, 2007 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Hall, William F., Jr. (memorial), 2001 November 8 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Hamilton, Marci, 1999 November 3 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Hannum, John (memorial), 2007 May 2 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Hastie, Jr., William H. (regarding), 2011 (Box 12, Folder 6-7)
  - Hazard, Jr., Geoffrey C., 1997-2003 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Hearn, Peter, 2006 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Helen, Undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Henkin, Louis and Alice, 2010 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Hershman Barbara Anne and Walter R. Felton (wedding), 2002 February 2 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Hibbett, Howard, 2003 January 2 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Higginbotham, A. Leon, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1983-2006 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Hutton, Herbert, J. (memorial), 2007 April 13 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Jefferson, Thomas, 1985-1998 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Jessup, Philip, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Jones, Mary Gardiner, 2007 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Jones, Nathaniel R., 2005 May 18 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Kalman, Laura, 2003-2005 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Karnow, Curtis E. A., 2002-2004 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Kendall, David and Anne, 2003 January 18 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Kentridge, Sydney, 2001 June 1 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - King, Martin Luther, Jr. (regarding), 1986-2006 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Kirby, Michael, 2000-2001 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Koh, Harold Hongju, 2004-2009 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Levin, A. Leo, 1998 December (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Levitt, Martin Lee, 2004 January (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Levy, Robert J., 2001-2002 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Lewis, Anthony, 1996-2009 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Linde, Hans, 1972-1992 (Box 14, Folder 7-8)
  - Lipson, Leon, 1996-2005 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Magnuson, Eric J., 2001-2010 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - MaGuire, Sarah, Undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Mansmann, Carol Los (memorial), 2002 April 29 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Maris, Albert B., 1989-1990 (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
  - Marsh, James, 1999-2006 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Marshall, John, 2006 (Box 15, Folder 4-5)
  - Marshall, Thurgood (regarding), 1993-2004 (Box 16, Folder 1-4)
  - Massiah-Jackson, Frederica, 1998 March 10 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - McCray, Simona Pekelis, 2005 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Meyerson, Martin, 2007 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Mitchell, Clarence and Juanita, 1981 September 25 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Montgomery, Robert H, Jr. (memorial), 2000 September 26 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Morris, Clarence, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Motley, Constance Baker, 2004-2009 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Paulsen, Monrad G., 1981-1982 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Perlin, Adam A., 2010-2011 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Posner, Nathan, 2009, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Post, Robert, 2004 October 25 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Powell, Jefferson, 2011-2012 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Prashad, Ashoka, 1990 August 2 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Preiskel, Robert, 1996-2007 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Putnam, Alfred W., Jr., 2001-2011 (Box 18, Folder 1-4)
  - Rabin, Yitzhak (regarding), Undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Rabinowitz, Alan and Andrea, 2004-2005 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Reese, Willis L. M., 1991 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Rehnquist., William H., 1997, 2005 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Reinhardt, Stephen J., 2009 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Reinstein, Robert, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Rendell, Edward G. (regarding), 2003 January 21 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Rendell, Majorie O. (regarding), 2003-2004, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Resnik, Judith, 2005 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Restrepo, Luis F., 2006 June 29 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Rosen, May, 2000-2006 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Rosenblatt, Albert, 2006-2007 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Rostow, Eugene V., 1986-2003, undated (Box 20, Folder 1-3)
  - Rufe, Cynthia, 2009 December 17 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Rutledge, Wiley B., 1992-2009 (Box 21, Folder 2-4)
  - Sawyer, Henry B., 1999 (Box 21, Folder 5-6)
  - Scheppele, Kim Lane, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Schlefer, Mark P., 1999-2000 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Segal, Bernard G., 1980-1997 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Seitz, Collins J., 1984-1999 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Shestack, Jerome J., 1991-1999 (Box 22, Folder 5-7)
  - Siegler, Ralph, 1993 July 22 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Silverman, Samuel J., 2001 March (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Simon, Samuel R., 2005 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Sirica, Anthony J., 2010-2011 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Sloviter, Delores K., 1983-2007 (Box 23, Folder 5-6)
  - Smith, George B., 2006 June 21 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Specter, Arlen (regarding), 2011 April 20 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Stapelton, Walter, 2000-2010 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Stern, Carl, 2001 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Strout, Cushing, 2002 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Summers, Clyde W., 2011 (Box 24, Folder 5-7)
  - Surrick, MaryAnn and Scott Popma (wedding), 2005 September 10 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Taft, Seth and Francis, 2010 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Tatel, David S., 2007-2009 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Taylor, Telford, 2001 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Thompson, Anne E., 2006 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Topkis, Jay, 2004 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Traynor, Michael, 2008 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Vermeil, Dick, 1999 October 15 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Waldman, Jay C., 2003-2004 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Warren, Earl (regarding), 2006 August 31 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Weinstein, Jack, 1977, 2006 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - White, Bryon, 2002 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Wisdom, John Minor, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Wolf, Morris, 1979 January 18 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Wolfman, Bernard, 2000 June 20 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Woodward, C. Vann, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Wyman, Lowry, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Yarmolinsky, Adam, 1997-2000 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Zeldes, Jacob D., 1971, 2003-2004 (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Chronological correspondence, 1965-1990, 2003-2004; Series II
  This series consists of correspondence that mostly spans the earlier period of Louis Pollak's career as an attorney, legal scholar, and judge. Like the alphabetical correspondence series, these materials mostly pertain to Pollak's scholarly work and professional engagement, through writing, speaking engagements, and discussions with colleagues about important legal issues of the day, and also includes a substantial body of correspondence from the mid-to-late 1970s.
  The papers are arranged chronologically.
  - Letterbook
    - 1965 September 22-1966 March 17 (Box 27, Folder 1-3)
    - #500-882, 1966 March 17-June 30 (Box 27, Folder 4-5)
    - 1966 July 1-November 23 (Box 27, Folder 6-7)
    - 1966 November 28-1967 December 27 (Box 28, Folder 1-5)
    - 1968 January 2-June 30 (Box 28, Folder 6-7)
    - 1968 July 1-December 31 (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
    - 1969 January 2-1970 June 30 (Box 30, Folder 1-6)
    - 1974 September 25-1975 February 14 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - 1975 January 22-June 2 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Personal
    - 1975 July-1978 August (Box 31, Folder 3-4)
    - 1978 September-1979 June (Box 31, Folder 5-7)
    - 1979 July-December (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - 1980 January-December (Box 32, Folder 2-3)
  - 1981 January-June (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - 1981 July-1983 June (Box 33, Folder 1-6)
  - 1983 July-1984 June (Box 34, Folder 1-3)
  - 1984 July-1985 December (Box 35, Folder 1-5)
  - 1986 January-1987 June (Box 36, Folder 1-6)
  - 1987 July-1988 December (Box 37, Folder 1-6)
  - 1989 January-1990 July (Box 38, Folder 1-5)
  - 2003-2004 (Box 39, Folder 1-3)
- Subject files, 1948-2010; Series III
  This series includes an assortment of materials related to Louis Pollak's professional life, research interests, and legal scholarship. Of note are files pertaining to Abernathy v. Alabama, a key civil rights lawsuit that Pollak argued before the United States Supreme Court.
  - General, 1948-1973 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Abernathy v. State of Alabama, 1961-1965 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Bakke case, 1976-1978 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Bickel, Alexander M., 1965-1970 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Biddle lecture, spring 1981, 1980 October-1983 March (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Bill of Rights, 1991 October (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Black Law Students Association dinner, 1974 April-May (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Brazil, 1971-1975 (Box 41, Folder 1-2)
  - Capital punishment, 1973 March-May (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Carswell, G. Harrold, 1970 January-June (Box 41, Folder 4-5)
  - Carswell nomination, 1970 January-March (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Coleman, William, Honorable, 1991-1999 (Box 41, Folder 7-8)
  - Committee on Privacy (UK), 1971 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Conference on Civil Rights Act of 1964, Washington, D.C., November 11-12, 1994 September 22-November 12 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Conference on the Media and the Law
    - Santa Barbara, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - United Kingdom, June 24-26, 1977 March-December (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Constitution and the Supreme Court: A Documentary History, comments from readers, 1966-1969 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Constitution works, 1996-1999 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - CW Alumnae Society speech draft, 1976 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Dash, Samuel (Widgery Tribunal), 1972 June 2 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - England, 1992 September (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Exeter High School Reunion, April 28-30, 1999 September-2000 May (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Federal Judicial Nominating Commission, 1977 November-1978 July (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Flag burning, 1989-1991 (Box 43, Folder 2-3)
  - Flag Burning II, 1989-1995 (Box 44, Folder 1-3)
  - Fortas, Abe, 1966-1973 (Box 44, Folder 4-5)
  - Freedman versus Maryland, 1963-1965 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - General Assembly of Pennsylvania, House Bill No. 71, 1977 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - General notes and writing drafts from England, Circa 1982 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Hastie, William H., 1971-1978 (Box 45, Folder 4-5)
  - Haynsworth nomination, 1969 October-December (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Heinz/Schweiker Judicial Selection Commission, 1977 March-April (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Higginbotham, J., 1997-1999 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Hilldale Lecture (University of Wisconsin), 1975 November-1976 April (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Interights, Bangalore, 28-30 December 1998, 1994-1999 (Box 46, Folder 1-2)
  - Interrogatories, Loyalty Security Board, 1952-1957 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Jessup, Philip C., 1955-1973 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Judgeship letters of congratulations, 1978 (Box 46, Folder 5-6)
  - "Law and Liberty: The American Constitution and the Doctrine That All Men Are Created Equal," Law School at University of Tel Aviv, 1971 March 8 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Law Education and Participation (LEAP), 1974-1978 (Box 47, Folder 2-3)
  - Law Education and Participation (LEAP) by-laws, 1976 November 15 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Lawyers' Committee for Civil Rights Under Law, Biko Inquest, Pretoria, South Africa, November 1977, 1977-1978 (Box 47, Folder 5-6)
  - Legal Defense Fund
    - Capital Punishment, 1971 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Philadelphia Campaign, 1972-1978 (Box 47, Folder 8-9)
  - Letter to The Evening Bulletin (Philadelphia, PA) re: Judges Becker, Fogel, and Green, February 27, 1978 February-March (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - LeVine, Robert T., 1965 August-September (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Michigan Law Review foreward, 1993-1995 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Motion Picture Association of America, 1978 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP)
    - Davis, Angela, 1971 June-July (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Legal Defense, McLaughlin case, 1963-1978 (Box 49, Folder 2-3)
  - New Haven Board of Education
    - Racial imbalance, 1963-1966 (Box 49, Folder 4-6)
    - School prayer, 1963-1965 (Box 49, Folder 7-8)
  - Oxford Colloquium in September 1992, 1991 December-1992 November (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Panama Canal Treaties, January 1978, 1977 October-1978 May (Box 50, Folder 2-3)
  - Plessy v. Ferguson, 1895 (photocopy), Undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Polier lecture, 1992 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Pollak, Louis H., deanship (on retirement), 1969 September-1970 July (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Presidential candidates, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Public matters, 1962-1974 (Box 51, Folder 5-7)
    Material includes letters to editors and statements regarding public matters.
  - Recurring Issues in Death Penalty Cases
    - Reference material and memorandum, 2000 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Part One: Pretrial Phase [commercially produced], 2000; 1 (Box 52)
    - Part Two: Trial and Penalty Phases [commercially produced], 2000; 1 (Box 53)
  - References and endorsements, 1996-1998 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - The Reporter book reviews (unpublished): John P. Frank, The Marble Palace and Alpheus T. Mason, Supreme Court from Taft to Warren, 1959 March 30 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Rostow, Eugene V., Dean, 1964 October 5-1973 February 16 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Russia
    General
    See also: Soviet Union, box 56, folders 1-4.
    - 1991 November 9-17 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - 1992 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - S. 354 (National No-Fault Motor Vehicle Insurance Act), 1974 October (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Salzburg Seminar, July 31-August 7, 1999, 1998-2002 (Box 54, Folder 4-6)
  - Sampson versus Kennedy (Bork correspondence), 1974 October-1975 March (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Segregation, 1954 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Southern Africa, 1978-1995 (Box 55, Folder 2-4)
  - Soviet Union (U.S.S.R.)
    See also: Russia, box 54, folders 1-2.
    - 1991 May 21-25 (Box 56, Folder 1-3)
    - 1991 November (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Speeches (miscellaneous), 1965-1974 (Box 56, Folder 5-6)
  - Spycatcher, 1987 July-October (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Strengthening World Law, 1988-1991 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Supreme Court vacancies, 1971-1972 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Trumbull Lectures, 1963-1966 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - United Nations Association (UNA) Panel on Human Rights, 1978-1979 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - United States ex rel Harold D. Rogers v. Mark S. Richmond, 1957-1958 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - University of Chicago book review, 1985-1988 (Box 57, Folder 7-8)
  - University of Iowa, April 1988, 1986 December-1988 May (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - University of Michigan Law School, Association of American Law Schools (AALS) reinspection, March 1978, 1978 March-July (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - University of Pennsylvania Greenfield Professorship -- miscellaneous letters regarding acceptance of chair, 1973 February 16-October 15 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Watergate, 1973 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Wechsler piece, 1959-1960 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Widgery hearings, 1972 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Wilson, Woodrow, 2007, 2010 (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Wyoming lecture (flag salute), 11 November 1988, 1987-1995 (Box 58, Folder 7-8)
  - Yale lecture (final) re: Anderson Fellow, 2004 April 20 (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Yale Law Journal, "The Antagonists", 1990-1991 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Yale Law School commencement address, 1968 June 10 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Yale Law School matters, 1955-1972 (Box 59, Folder 3)
- Supreme Court Justices files, 1989-2012; Series IV